Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, baron, 1809-1892., 21 envelopes (Box 7, Item 45)
    - A Dream of Fair Women. "I read, before my eyelids dropt their shade" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 5)
    - The Dying Swan. "The plain was grassy, wild and bare" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 5)
    - The Eagle. "He clasps the crag with crooked hands;" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 5)
    - The Eagle. "He clasps the crag with crooked hands," continued (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - Edward Gray. "Sweet Emma Moreland of yonder town" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - 1865-1866. "I stood on a tower in the wet" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - Enoch Arden. "Long lines of cliff breaking have left a chasm;" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - A Farewell. "Flow down, cold rivulet, to the sea" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - The Fleet. "You, you, if you shall fail to understand" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - "Flower in the crannied wall" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - 'Frater Ave Atque Vale'. "Row us out from Desenzano, to your Sirmione row!" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 6)
    - Godiva. "I waited for the train at Coventry;" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - The Grandmother. "And Willy, my eldest-born, is gone, you say, little Anne?" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - Guinevere. "No light: so late! and dark and chill the night!" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - Hands All Round. "First pledge our Queen this solemn night" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - The Higher Pantheism. "The sun, the moon, the stars, the seas, the hills and the plains--" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - Home They Brought Her Warrior Dead. "Home they brought her warrior dead:" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - Idylls of the King. "So the stately Queen abode" and "These to his memory--since he held them dear" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 7)
    - Idylls of the King, continued. (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 8)
    - In Memoriam. (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 9)
    - In the Garden at Swainston. "Nightingales warbled without" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 9)
    - The Kraken. "Below the thunders of the upper deep;" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 9)
    - Lady Clara Vere de Vere. "Lady Clara Vere de Vere" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 9)
    - Lady Clara Vere de Vere. "Lady Clara Vere de Vere," continued (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 10)
    - The Lady of Shalott. "On either side the river lie" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 10)
    - Lilian. "Airy, fairy Lilian" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 10)
    - Locksley Hall. "Comrades, leave me here a little, while as yet 'tis early morn;" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 10)
    - Locksley Hall. "Comrades, leave me here a little, while as yet 'tis early morn:" continued (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 11)
    - The Lord of Burleigh. "In her ear he whispers gayly" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - The Lotus-Eaters. "There is sweet music here that softer falls" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - "Love that hath us in the net" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - "Love that hath us in the net" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - "Love thou thy land, with love far-brought" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - Margaret, "O sweet pale Margaret" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - Mariana. "With blackest moss the flower-plots" (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - Maud. (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 12)
    - Untitled. (Box 7, Item 45, Envelope 13)
    - The May Queen. "You must wake and call me early, call me early, mother dear;" (Box 8, Envelope 14)
    - The May Queen. "You must wake and call me early, call me early, mother dear;" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - Merlin and Vivien. "A storm was coming, but the winds were still," also "In Love, if Love by Love, if Love be ours" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - The Mermaid. "Who would be" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - The Merman. "Who would be" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - The Miller's Daughter. "It is the miller's daughter" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - Milton. "O mighty-mouth'd inventor of harmonies" (Box 8, Envelope 15)
    - Montenegro. "They rose to where their Sovran eagle sails" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - Morte d'Arthur. (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - O Darling Room. "O darling room, my heart's delight" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - Ode on the Death of the Duke of Wllington. "Bury the Great Duke" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - Oenone. "There lies a vale in Ida, lovelier" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - "Of old sat Freedom on the heights" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - On the Jubilee of Queen Victoria. "Fifty times the rose has flower'd and faded" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - Opening of the Indian and Colonial Exhibition By the Queen. "Welcome, welcome with one voice!" (Box 8, Envelope 16)
    - The Owl. "When cats run home and light is come" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Palace of Art. "I built my soul a lordly pleasure house" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Poet. "The poet in a golden clime was born" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Poet's Song. "The rain had fallen, the Poet arose" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Prefatory Sonnet to the 'Nineteenth Century'. "Those that of late had fleeted far and fast" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Princess. (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Promise of May. "The town lay still in the low sun-light" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Recollections of the Arabian Nights. "When the breeze of a joyful dawn blew free" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Revenge. "At Flores in the Azores Sir Richard Grenville lay" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Rizpah. "Wailing, wailing, wailing, the wind over land and sea--" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Sir John Franklin. "Not here! the white North has thy bones; and thou" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Sisters. "We were two daughters of one race:" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - The Skipping Rope. "Sure never yet was Antelope" (Box 8, Envelope 17)
    - Song of the Brook. "I come from haunts of coot and hern" (Box 8, Envelope 18)
    - The Spiteful Letter. "Here, it is here, the close of the years" (Box 8, Envelope 18)
    - "The splendor falls on castle walls" (Box 8, Envelope 18)
    - "The splendor falls on castle walls" continued (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - "Sweet and low, sweet and low!" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - The Talking Oak. "Once more the gate behind me falls;" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - Timbuctoo. "I stood upon the Mountain wich o'erlooks" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - Tithonus. "The woods decay, the woods decay and fall" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - To H.R.H. Princess Beatrice. "Two Suns of Love make day of human life" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - "Turn, Fortune, turn thy wheel and lower the proud;" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - The Two Voices. "A still, small voice spake unto me" (Box 8, Envelope 19)
    - Ulysses. "It little profits that an idle king" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - The Victim. "A plague upon the people fell" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - The Vision of Sin. (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - The Voyage. "We left behind the painted buoy" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - Wages. "Glory of warrior, glory of orator, glory of song" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - The War. "There is a sound of thunder afar" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - A Welcome to Alexandria. "Sea-kings' daughter from over the sea" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - What Does Little Birdie Say. "What does little birdie say" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - Will Waterproof's Lyrical Monologue. "O plump head-waiter at The Cock" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - "You ask me, why, tho' ill at ease" (Box 8, Envelope 20)
    - Parodies in the style of Tennyson, original poems unidentified. (Box 8, Envelope 21)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Age of Wisdom. "Ho, pretty page, with the dimpled chin" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Battle of Limerick. "Ye Genii of the nation" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Domestic Love Song. "In tattered old slippers that toast at the bars" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - Little Billee. "There were three sailors of Bristol city" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Mahogany Tree. "Christmas is here:" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Sorrows of Werther. "Werther had a love for Charlotte" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - The Willow-tree. "Know ye the willow-tree" (Box 8, Item 1)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 1)
  - "There is a happy land", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 2)
  - "There was a little man", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 3)
  - "There's a land that bears a well-known name", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 4)
  - Thompson, Francis, 1859-1907., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 5)
    - Parody in the style of Thompson, original poem unidentified. (Box 8, Item 5)
  - Thomson, James, 1834-1882., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 6)
    - Gifts. "Give a man a horse he can ride" (Box 8, Item 6)
    - Rule Britannia. "When Britain first at Heaven's command" (Box 8, Item 6)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 6)
  - The Three Ravens. "There were three ravens sat on a tree", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 7)
  - "Trust not man for he'll deceive you", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 8)
  - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 9)
    - Parodies in the style of Tupper, original poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 9)
  - The Two Obadiahs., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 10)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 11)
    - Parody in the style of Untermeyer, original poem unidentified. (Box 8, Item 11)
  - Upton, James, 1670-1749., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 12)
    - The Lass of Richmond Hill. "On Richmond Hill there lives a lass" (Box 8, Item 12)
  - "The Vicar of Bray. "In good King Charles's golden", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 13)
  - Wade, Joseph Augustine, 1796?-1845., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 14)
    - Meet Me By Moonlight Alone. "Meet me by moonlight alone" (Box 8, Item 14)
  - The Wail of the Rejected. "Oh dear! I'm nearly thirty." (Box 8, Item 15)
  - Waller, Edmund, 1606-1687., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 16)
    - Go, Lovely Rose! "Go, lovely Rose!" (Box 8, Item 16)
    - On a Girdle. "That which he slender waist confined" (Box 8, Item 16)
    - Under a Lady's Picture. "Such Helen was! and who can blame the boy" (Box 8, Item 16)
  - Waller, Edmund, 1606-1687., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 17)
    - Of My Lady Isabella Playing the Lute. "Such moving sounds from such a careless touch!" (Box 8, Item 17)
    - The Story of Phoebus and Daphne Applied. "Thyrsis, a youth of the inspired train" (Box 8, Item 17)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 17)
  - Walsh, William, 1663-1708., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 18)
    - Song. "Of all the torments, all the cares" (Box 8, Item 18)
  - Walton, Izack, 1593-1683., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 19)
    - The Angler's Wish. "I in these flowery meads would be;" (Box 8, Item 19)
  - Wanted - A Governess. "A Governess wanted - well fitted to fill", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 20)
  - Warren, Samuel, 1807-1877., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 21)
    - The Lily and the Bee. (Box 8, Item 21)
  - Watson, James W., 1775-1820., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 22)
    - Beautiful Snow. "Oh! the snow, the beautiful snow" (Box 8, Item 22)
  - Watson, William, 1858-1935., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 23)
    - "I do not ask to have my fill" (Box 8, Item 23)
    - The Key-Board. "Five-and-thirty black slaves" (Box 8, Item 23)
    - They and We. "With stormy joy, from height on height" (Box 8, Item 23)
    - To Theodore Roosevelt. "I hear a mighty people asking now" (Box 8, Item 23)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 23)
  - Watts, Isaac, 1674-1748., 3 envelopes (Box 8, Item 24)
    - Against Idleness and Mischief. "How doth the little busy bee" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 1)
    - Against Quarreling and Fighting. "Let dogs delight to bark and bite" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 1)
    - Against Quarreling and Fighting. "Let dogs delight to bark and bite" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 2)
    - Innocent Play. "Abroad in the meadows to see the young lambs" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 2)
    - Praise for mercies spiritual and temporal. "Whene'er I take my walks abroad" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 2)
    - The Sluggard. "'Tis the voice of sluggard; I heard him complain" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 2)
    - The Sluggard. "'Tis the voice of the sluggard; I heard him complain" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 3)
    - The Thief. "'Tis a foolish self-deceiving" (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 3)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 24, Envelope 3)
  - We Are A Merry Family. "I am the pink of properness, and whereso'er I roam", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 25)
  - The Wearing of the Green. "O Paddy dear, and did you hear the news that's going 'round?", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 26)
  - Weatherly, Frederick Edward, 1848-?, 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 27)
    - Darby and Joan. "Darby, dear, we are old and gray" (Box 8, Item 27)
    - The Old Brigade. "Where are the boys of the Old Brigade." (Box 8, Item 27)
    - "There were three young maids of Lee" (Box 8, Item 27)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 27)
  - Wharton, Thomas, 1648-1715., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 28)
    - Lilli Berlero. "Ho! Broder Teague, dost hear de decree" (Box 8, Item 28)
  - What is a Woman Like? "A woman is like to - but stay -", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 29)
  - What Is the German's Fatherland? "What is the German's Fatherland?", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 30)
  - When the Tide Comes In., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 31)
  - When This Old Cap Was New. "When this old cap was new-", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 32)
  - When We Went Out a Gipsying. "In the days when we went gipsying.", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 33)
  - White, Henry Kirke, 1785-1806., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 34)
    - To Love. "Why should I blush to own I love?" (Box 8, Item 34)
  - Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892., 3 envelopes (Box 8, Item 35)
    - Parodies in the style of Whitman, original poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 35, Envelope 1)
    - Parodies in the style of Whitman, original poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 35, Envelope 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Whitman, original poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 35, Envelope 3)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 36)
    - Barbara Frietchie. "Up from the meadows rich with corn" (Box 8, Item 36)
    - Maud Muller. "Maud Muller, on a summer's day" (Box 8, Item 36)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 36)
  - Whyte-Melville, G. J., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 37)
    - The Galloping Squire. "Come, I'll show you a country that none can surpass" (Box 8, Item 37)
    - Good-bye! "Falling leaf, and fading tree" (Box 8, Item 37)
    - It came with the merry May, Love" (Box 8, Item 37)
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler, 1855-1919., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 38)
    - Blasé. "The world had outlived all its passion" (Box 8, Item 38)
    - My Ships. "If all the ships I have at sea" (Box 8, Item 38)
    - Temptation and explanation. "I just buttoned her glove" (Box 8, Item 38)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 38)
  - Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 39)
    - The Burden of Itys. (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Chanson. "A ring of gold and a milk-white dove" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - The harlot's house. "We caught the tread of dancing feet" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Impression. "The sky is laced with fitful red" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Impressions -- La Fuite de la Lune. "To outer senses there is peace" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Theocritus. "O Singer of Persephone!" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Theoretikos. "This mighty empire hath but feet of clay:" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - Under the Balcony. "O beautiful star with the crimson mouth!" (Box 8, Item 39)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 39)
  - Wilkinson, Marguerite Ogden (Bigelow) 1883-1928., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 40)
    - Pawnbrokers! "God bless pawnbrokers!" (Box 8, Item 40)
  - Williams, Charles Hanbury, 1708-1759., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 41)
    - Ode to the Earl of Bath. "Great Earl of Bath, your reign is o'er;" (Box 8, Item 41)
    - "Dear Netty, come give me sweet kisses" (Box 8, Item 41)
  - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, 1806-1867., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 42)
    - The Annoyer. "Love knoweth every form of air" (Box 8, Item 42)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 42)
  - Winter, William, 1836-1917., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 43)
    - Asleep. "He knelt beside her pillow" (Box 8, Item 43)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 43)
  - Wolfe, Charles., 2 envelopes (Box 8, Item 44)
    - The Burial of Sir John Moore. "Not a drum was heard, not a funeral note" (Box 8, Item 44, Envelope 1)
    - The Burial of Sir John Moore. "Not a drum was heard, not a funeral note," Continued. (Box 8, Item 44, Envelope 2)
  - "A woman having a settlement", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 45)
  - Woodworth, Samuel, 1785-1842., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 46)
    - The Old Oaken Bucket. "How dear to this heart are the scenes of my childhood" (Box 8, Item 46)
  - Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850., 4 envelopes (Box 8, Item 47)
    - Alice Fell. "The post-boy drove with fierce career" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Anecdote for Fathers. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Character of the Happy Warrior. "Who is the happy warrior? Who is he" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Composed upon Westminster Bridge, Sept. 3, 1803. "Earth has not anything to shew more fair:" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Daffodils. "I wander'd lonely as a Cloud" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Desultory Stanzas. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - "Great men have been among us; hands that penned" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Intimations of Immortality. "There was a time when meadows, grove, and stream" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Louisa. "I met Louisa in the shade" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Lucy. "She dwelt among the untrodden ways" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Lucy Gray. "Oft I had heard of Lucy Gray:" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Milton! thou shouldst be living at this hour:" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - We Are Seven. "A simple child" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Within King's College Chapel, Cambridge. "Tax not the royal Saint with vain expense" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - "The world is too much with us; late and soon" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Written in Early Spring. "I heard a thousand blended notes" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Written in March. "The Cock is crowing" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Yarrow unvisited. "From Stirling Castle we had seen" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 3)
    - "My heart leaps up when I behold" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - Old Cumberland Beggar. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - The Pet Lamb. "The dew was falling fast, the stars began to blink;" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - Peter Bell. "There's something in a flying horse" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - The Reaper. "Behold her single in the field" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - The Redbreast and the Butterfly, "Art thou the bird whom man loves best" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - The Reverie of Poor Susan. "At the corner of Wood Street, when daylight appears" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - She was a Phantom of Delight. "She was a Phantom of delight" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - Sonnet. "Scorn not the Sonnet: Critic, you have frown'd" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - To a butterfly. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - To a cuckoo. "O blithe new-comer! I have heard" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - To my Sister. (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - Thought of a Briton on the Subjugation of Switzerland. "Two voices are there - one is of the sea" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
    - "Up, up, my friend" (Box 8, Item 47, Envelope 4)
  - Wotton, Sir Henry, 1568-1639., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 48)
    - Elizabeth of Bohemia. "You meaner beauties of the night" (Box 8, Item 48)
  - "Write me a letter from home", 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 49)
    - "Write me a letter from home" (Box 8, Item 49)
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1865-1939., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 50)
    - The Lake Isle of Innisfree. I will arise and go now, and go to Innisfree" (Box 8, Item 50)
    - When you are old. "When you are old and gray and full of sleep" (Box 8, Item 50)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 50)
  - Young, Edward, 1683-1765., 1 envelope (Box 8, Item 51)
    - General. (Box 8, Item 51)
  - Unidentified parodies., 7 envelopes (Box 8, Item 52)
    - 43 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 1)
    - 42 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - 45 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 3)
    - 46 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 4)
    - 47 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - 47 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 6)
    - 16 parodies, source poems unidentified. (Box 8, Item 52, Envelope 7)